A Guide to the Alfred E. Cohn papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA802 FA802
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Alfred E. Cohn papers, Rockefeller University Faculty, 45 record storage cartons, 1 oversize box.
  - University of Chicago Press (Box 17)
    - [review of three essays on Vesalius by S.W. Lambert, W. Wiegand, and W.M. Ivins, Jr.], 1949 (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - [New York Heart Association Comms] (Box 17)
    - Exhibits sent to Board of Directors Feb 5/1948 [correspondence and memoranda re New York Heart Association: criticism of Research Committee's work and Cohn resignation, 1945-48] (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - Park, Edwards A. Pediatric Clinic (Holt and Wood) (Box 17, Folder 31-32)
    - Dr. Park, 1927-1932 (Box 17, Folder 31)
    - Dr. Holt and Dr. Wood, 1928 (Box 17, Folder 32)
    - Physicians in Industry Dr. Rector. Dr. Schubmehl Dr. Crain Dr. Knapp, 1928-1930 (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - Group for the Advancement of Psychiatry [circulars], circa 1948-1949 (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - International Physiological Congresses (Box 17, Folder 35)
    [correspondence, programs, travel arrangements, publication proc.].
    - 13th Boston with visit to NYC including RIMR, 1929
    - 14th (Naples?), 1932
    - 15th Leningrad-Moscow, 1934
    - Folder includes post card invitation to International Congress of History of Medicine, Madrid, 1935
  - New York Academy of Medicine (Box 17)
    - [Booklets on the Academy] (Box 17, Folder 36)
      [Material from envelope re publication of Vesalius Atlas (Wiegand) ca 1935].
    - [Correspondence, circular letters, invitations, memoranda, reports, agendas], circa 1928-1935 (Box 17, Folder 37)
    - [Nominations Brown-Webb] (Box 17, Folder 38)
    - Notices of meetings, memoranda, minutes, agendas, 1929-1934 (Box 17, Folder 39)
    - Notices of meetings, memoranda, minutes, agendas, 1935 (Box 17, Folder 40)
    - Library Committee, 1929-1934 (Box 17, Folder 41)
    - Library Committee, 1935 (Box 17, Folder 42)
      [includes correspondence re Vesalian Atlas].
  - Joint Distribution Committee/ Hadassah Medical Organization, circa 1921-1925 (Box 18)
    - [Memo re Sub-Carpathia], circa 1921-1922 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Final report and contract, circa 1922 (Box 18, Folder 2)
      [includes carbon of 12-page holograph, Cohn/Bernard Flexner, 29 July 1922, and drafts of Cohn report on trip to Palestine to study medical and sanitary requirements].
    - Malaria Research Unit (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Palestine, 1923 (Box 18, Folder 3)
      [Correspondence, memoranda with G.W. Heron, 1923].
    - Hadassah Medical Organization (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Statistics, 1922-1923 (Box 18, Folder 4)
      [Filed with Cohn legal size].
    - Hadassah Medical Organization. ca 1921-22 [Reports, memoranda, pamphlets (some in Hebrew), correspondence] [Filed with Cohn legal size], circa 1921-1922 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Hadassali Medical Organization (Box 18, Folder 6)
      Includes correspondence with I.M. Rubinow ca 1922-1923.
    - Governing Board of the Hadassah Hospitals in Palestine, 1923 December-1924 May (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Governing Board of the Hadassah Hospitals in Palestine, 1924 June-1925 February (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Governing Board (Box 18, Folder 9-11)
      [various matters, ca 1923-24, no chronological or series order. Includes correspondence, minutes, reports, etc].
    - Joint Distribution Committee. Medical Committee, 1921-1924 (Box 18, Folder 12)
      [Includes typescripts by Cohn of "Prefatory Note" to Kligler paper, ca 1924. Also includes Proceedings of the 8th meeting of the Antimalarial Advisory Commission, 22 Nov 1923. 14 pp]. [Filed with Cohn legal size]. Med. Comm.
    - Joint Distribution Committee, 1923 (Box 18, Folder 13-14)
      [Includes report, June 1923, and photograph of Training School for Nurses, Warsaw] - not in file.
    - Joint Distribution Committee. Medical Committee, 1921-1922 (Box 18, Folder 15-17)
    - Joint Distribution Committee. Unpublished [Agenda, correspondence, circa 1921-1923 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Joint Distribution Committee. Incoming, circa 1921-1922 (Box 18, Folder 19-21)
    - [Minutes of European Executive Council held at Paris, 1922 February 23 1922 March 1-2 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Joint Distribution Committee. Executive Committee. [Minutes Dec 1921-Jun 1922], 1921 December-1922 June (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Joint Distribution Committee. Notes and letters, circa 1922 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - Joint Distribution Committee. Cables, 1921-1922 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - Joint Distribution Committee. Outgoing, 1921 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - China Medical Board/Peiping Union Medical College ca 1940-53 [This file was previously worked on by Ruth Sternfeld] (Box 18)
    - C.M.B. Minutes of meetings, 1943 (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - C.M.B. Minutes of meetings, 1944 (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - C.M.B. Minutes of meetings, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - C.M.B. Annual report, 1943-1945 1952-1953 (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - C.M.B. By-laws 1940, amended, 1943-1944 (Box 18, Folder 31)
    - C.M.B. Financial report, 1943-1944 1950-1951 (Box 18, Folder 32)
    - C.M.B. Budget proposals, 1940-1941 (Box 18, Folder 33)
    - C.M.B. Special reports [Accountant's report for the year ended Dec 31, 1944 filed with Cohn legal size] (Box 18, Folder 34)
    - C.M.B. Docket of meetings, 1944-1945 (Box 18, Folder 35-36)
    - Peiping Union Medical College Minutes of meetings, 1943-1945 (Box 18, Folder 37)
    - P.U.M.C.E.C. Lobenstine, 1940 (Box 18, Folder 38)
    - P.U.M.C.E.C. Lobenstine, 1941 (Box 18, Folder 39)
    - P.U.M.C.E.C. Lobenstine, 1942 (Box 18, Folder 40)
    - P.U.M.C.E.C. Lobenstine, 1943-June 1945 (Box 18, Folder 41)
    - P.U.M.C. Agnes M. Pearce, 1940-1951 (Box 18, Folder 42)
  - China Medical Board/Peiping Union Medical College (Box 19)
    - Yu Wang Fu Association (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Address lists
      - 1927-1934 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - 1940-1947 (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - 1948-1953 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Communications, circa 1927-1951 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Club for Research on Aging (Box 19)
    - Correspondence
      - 1939-1940 (Box 19, Folder 5)
      - 1941-1942 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - 1943-1945 (Box 19, Folder 7)
      - 1946-1950, undated (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - [Memoranda and projects] (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Meetings, 1940-1942 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Meetings, 1943-1945 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Carnegie Corporation of New York [re adult education] (Box 19)
    - Correspondence, 1924-1927 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - [Memoranda, reprints, pamphlets] (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Board of Economic Warfare (Box 19)
    - Correspondence, 1942 September-December (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1943-1944 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - [Notes, memoranda, clippings, reference card on sulfathiazole] (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - [Travel arrangements, expenses] (Box 19, Folder 17-18)
  - World's Fair, New York, 1940 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence re dismantling of Ciba exhibits, 1940-1941
      [Includes material on Cleveland Health Museum].
    - Plan of the Medical and Public Health Building, New York World's Fair 1939 (Drawer folder 6)
      oversize material
      These graphic materials have been separated for special housing in map drawers.
  - Atlantic Monthly (Box 19)
    - [Correspondence re responses to article by Albert Jay Nock, "The Jewish Problem in America"]
      Includes Felix Frankfurter correspondence and letter, Charles Beard/Frankfurter, 22 Sep 1941 (see FF/Cohn, 10 Oct 1941).
      - 1941 July-December (Box 19, Folder 20)
      - 1942 January-1943 May (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - New York Academy of Medicine, [In box 20, legal size folders arranged crosswise in box] (Box 19)
    - [Miscellaneous booklets, announcements, and correspondence], circa 1940-1941 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - [Papers from envelope: draft of Committee on Library report, background papers], 1939 December 8 (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - Library Committee [Minutes, correspondence re meetings], 1940-1942 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Council [Minutes], 1940 January-1942 January (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - Editorial Board. Dr. Ashford, 1940-1945 (Box 19, Folder 26)
      [Includes program for 1941 Graduate Fortnight, with Cohn lecture on rheumatic heart disease].
    - Preamble and resolution [re Academy policy on refugees] (Box 19)
      - Correspondence, 1941-1944 (Box 19, Folder 27)
        [Includes various Cohn memoranda; Rufus Cole/Cohn 13 Jan [1942] /Cohn to Felix frankfurter 25 Feb 1942].
      - [Carbon copies of correspondence file] (Box 19, Folder 28)
      - [Felix] Frankfurter, [Louis] Weiss, [Herbert B.] Wilcox, 1942 January-November (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - Wilcox, Dr. H.B., 1940-1945 (Box 19, Folder 30)
    - Dr. [Malcolm] Goodridge, 1940-1942 (Box 19, Folder 31)
    - [Archibald Malloch, Librarian], 1940 (Box 19, Folder 32)
    - [Archibald Malloch, Librarian], 1941 (Box 19, Folder 33)
    - [Archibald Malloch, Librarian], 1942 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - [Includes Malloch / Cohn, 18-19 Jan 1944, in tribute to Cohn], 1943-1945 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Miss [Janet] Doe [Assistant Librarian], 1940 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - [Report of Subcommittee on Duplicate Rare Books], 1940 November (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Trustees [Minutes], 1940-1941 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - [Miscellaneous reports, clippings, correspondence], circa 1940-1946 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Paeff, Bashka, 1935 November (Box 20, Folder 7-8)
    [re bas-relief of Simon Flexner, medal reproductions, and presentation dinner in honor of Dr. and Mrs. Flexner, Cosmopolitan Club. Includes photos of relief, planning correspondence with Florence R. Sabin].
  - [Cohn manuscripts from wooden file drawers] (Box 20)
    - Index of folders, manuscripts, [typescript with revisions] (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - [Charts, background material on heart disease statistics s], circa 1920 (Box 20, Folder 10-11)
    - Paper prepared for the Annual Staff Meeting of the R.I. Not published, 1914 January 9; [holograph, typescripts] (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Writings in France, 1918 (Box 20, Folder 13)
      - "The organization of a convalescent camp"
      - "The effort syndrome"
      - "Report on activities of cardio-vascular section"
      - Untitled re work of Medical Department
      - "Estimating the Importance of Systolic Murmurs"
      - AEF Weekly Bulletins
    - Cardiac neurosis, 1918 (Box 20, Folder 14)
      [Includes Francis W. Peabody/Cohn, 22 Aug 1918; "Report of cardio-vascular work at General Hospital No. 9, Lakewood, N.J. [1918]; copies of articles, letters, memos by others].
    - [Notes, drafts re effort syndrome] (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Effort syndrome notes, 1918 (Box 20, Folder 16)
      [Includes J. Mackenzie/Cohn, 20 Oct 1918].
    - Effort syndrome notes [II], 1918-1919 (Box 20, Folder 17)
      [Includes N.Y. Times clipping 24 Feb 1919, "Jews Point in Pride to Record in War, " letters in reply to Cohn requests for reprints, ca 1918-19].
    - [Notes, articles, letters on effort syndrome, 1919 (Box 20, Folder 18)
      Includes Paul D. White/Cohn, 15 Apr 1919].
    - [Notes, background material on effort syndrome, 1918 (Box 20, Folder 19)
      Includes stencil, "The Effort Syndrome... delivered to the Class of the Fourth Session, Army Sanitary School, April 29, 1918 by Major Alfred E. Cohn..."].
    - Cardiac phases of the war neuroses..., 1919 February (Box 20, Folder 20-21)
      [Manuscripts; includes "Preliminary notes for staff meeting "; published Am. J. Med. Sci. 1919].
    - Poisonous gases: Later Effects [Read at the section of Internal Medicine, A.M.A., Atlantic City, Not published], 1919 June 13 (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - The Effort Syndrome [Read at Johns Hopkins Medical Society], 1919 May 5 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - Memorandum on Medical Education (for Mr. Abraham Flexner), 1921 October (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - Address given at Montefiore Hospital [Charts and tables, news paper clippings, mss and program], 1922 April 23 (Box 20, Folder 25-26)
    - Clinical charts recommended by the Association for the Prevention and Relief of Heart Disease. The Plans for their Use. J.A.M.A., 1922 (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - The Use of Records. Hosp. Social Service, 1922 (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - Heart disease from the point of view of the public health, 1927 (Box 20)
      - [Corrected typescript and tables] (Box 20, Folder 29)
      - [Preliminary tables] (Box 20, Folder 30)
      - Topic notes on Heart Disease... (Box 20, Folder 31)
      - [Miscellaneous tables, mounted on card-board] (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - Cohn manuscripts, circa 1928-1938 (Box 21)
    - Chapter for E.V. Cowdry's "Special Cytology" on "Cardiac Muscle", 1928 (Box 21)
      - untitled, [Typescript and clippings] (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - [Illustrations] (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - ["The Development of the Harveian Circulation"], 1928 (Box 21)
      - [Holograph] (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - [Stencil of address, notes, illustrations, clippings, reprints of color illustrations] (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Degenerative forms of heart disease, 1931; [transcript, corrected typescript] (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Summary—Survey on Arteriosclerosis, 1932; [Typescript and holograph] (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Heart disease from the point of view of the public health (Box 21, Folder 7)
      [Includes typescripts, illustrations].
    - Coronary Thrombosis or Senescence: - A Case for Diagnosis. Libman Anniversary Vol. I, circa 1931-1932; [Typescript, holograph] (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Heart Disease from the point of view of the public health, 1933 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Amer. Heart Journal, 1934 (Box 21, Folder 9)
      [Includes typescripts, illustrations, correspondence].
    - Cohn and W.H. Lewis and J.M. Steele. The aging heart: man and dog. Staff meeting R.I. [Announcement and holograph], 1934 November 23 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - "What is Research?", 1934 December (Box 21, Folder 11)
      [Stencil, clipping, typescript, correspondence, holograph].
    - Introduction. The Course of Rheumatic Heart Disease in Adults De Graff and Lingg [, 1934 (Box 21, Folder 12)
      Includes typescript and holograph].
    - Theobald Smith, 1859-1934 (Box 21, Folder 13-14)
      [Includes reprint, typescripts, bibliography, holograph, clippings, obituaries].
    - Scholarship and Society, 1935 (Box 21, Folder 15-16)
      [Includes correspondence with Alvin Johnson, L.C. Dunn, American Scholar; typescripts, notes].
    - An analysis of the apparent increase in the heart diseases. Section Preventive and Industrial Medicine and Public Health. A.M.A. Atlantic City, 1935 June 14 (Box 21, Folder 17)
      [Includes correspondence, typescript, illustrations].
    - The value of research in disease of the heart, 1935 (Box 21, Folder 18)
      [Typescript, clipping, correspondence, holograph].
    - Introduction to Dr. Levy's book on Arteriosclerosis, circa 1935-1936 (Box 21, Folder 19-20)
      [Includes typescripts; letters re use of term "angina pectoris"; holograph].
    - The Value of Research in Chronic Diseases (Welfare Council -), 1936 January 22 (Box 21, Folder 21)
      [Includes typescripts, program, holograph].
    - The Meaning of Medical Research. Lecture to the Laity. NYA.M., 1937 November 24 (Box 21, Folder 22-23)
      [Includes galleys, typescripts, correspondence, program, clippings].
    - Cardiac diseases. Nosology of the Public Health. Anniversary vol. Joseph H. Pratt, 1937 (Box 21, Folder 24)
      [Includes proofs, typescripts, reprint, correspondence, holograph].
    - Heart Disease as a Public Health Problem. W.A.B.C., 1937 December 22; [Typescripts, holographs] (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - John Wyckoff, 1881-1937; [Typescripts, holographs, notes, program, reprint, proofs] (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - The Present Status of the Cardiac Diseases. Neighborhood Health 1938 IV No. 6 (Box 21, Folder 27)
      [Correspondence, typescript, holograph].
    - Homer F. Swift and Cohn. Cardiac diseases: Infectious and Non Infectious, Course and Consequences. Trans, and Studies Coll. Physn. Phila. ser 4. VI 197-215 and 215-227, 1938; [Typescript, notes] (Box 21, Folder 28)
    - No retreat form reason 9 Jan 1939, 1939 January 9 (Box 22, Folder 1-2)
      [Program, typescripts, correspondence, holographs, notes].
    - Cardiovascular system and Blood, [Galleys, typescripts, note cards, background material, correspondence] (Box 22, Folder 3-6)
    - Cohn and A.G. Macleod, The effect of acetylcholine on the mammalian heart. Am. Heart J. 17 305-315, 1939 (Box 22, Folder 7)
      [Typescripts, figures, correspondence, holograph notes].
    - Religio Medici, circa 1939-1940; Unfinished. Typescripts, holograph notes (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - W.P.A. aids in the study of Heart Disease. Broadcast Ap. 25, 1940 W.NY City 1:30 pm. (Box 22, Folder 9)
      [Typescript, correspondence].
    - Remarks on Professions in Medicine, 1940 January 24; [Galleys, typescripts, holographs, announcement] (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - The Influence of Modern Science on Painting and Sculpture. Met. Mus. Art, 1941 February 1 (Box 22, Folder 11)
      [Correspondence, announcement, partial typescript, holograph].
    - Changes in Public Attitudes toward Medicine - Historical Aspects Squibb Hall, 1941 April 3 (Box 22, Folder 12)
      [Announcements, typescripts, notes, H. Sigerist reprint, holograph, galley].
    - Psychoanalysis in Medicine. Pamphlet: Inst, for Psychoanalysis, Chicago, 1941 November (Box 22, Folder 13)
      [Galleys, typescripts, holograph].
    - G.E. Burch, Cohn, and Charles Neumann. A method for measuring the area of small irregular surfaces of the human body. Science 93 165, 1941; [Galley, figures, typescript] (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - G.E. Burch, Cohn, and C. Neumann, A study of the total volume of the human finger and toe tip. Human Biol. 13, 526. [Correspondence, galley], 1941 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - G.E. Burch, Cohn, and Charles Neumann, A study of the rate of water loss from the surface of the finger tips and toe tips of normal and senile subjects and patients with arterial hypertension. Am. Heart J. 23 185-196, 1942; [Galley, typescript, tables] (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - The Natural History of rheumatic Cardiac Disease. NY Acad. Med., 1941 October 23; [Program, correspondence, type scripts, figures, holographs] (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - G.E. Burch, Cohn, and C. Neumann, A study by quantitative methods of the spontaneous variations in volume of the finger tip. Am. J. Physiol, 1942; [Galley, page proof, typescript, figures, reprints] (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - C. Neumann, Cohn, and G.E. Burch A study of the relation between the pulse and alpha waves of the tips of the fingers and toes of five adults. A study by quantitative methods of the spontaneous variations in volume of the tips of fingers etc. Am. J. Physiol, 1942; [Galleys, holographs, typescripts, figures, reprint, page proofs] (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - The Natural History of Rheumatic Cardiac Disease. Cohn and C. Lingg. (J.A.M.A.), 1943; [Reprints, figures, typescripts] (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - The First Cardiac Clinic. (J.A.M.A. [Reprints, clipping, correspondence], 1943 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - C. Neumann, Cohn, and W.T. Lhamon. A study of the relation of emotional status to fluctuations (alpha waves) in volume of the finger tip. To be read before the New York Heart Assn, 1943 March 30 (Box 22, Folder 20)
      [Correspondence, typescripts].
    - Cohn, G.E. Burch, C. Neumann, E.A. Sellers, and W.T. Lhamon. Observations on changes in volume of small vessels in the finger and toes of normal young and old persons and in arterial hypertension. J. Mount Sinai Hosp. x 109-11, 1943 (Box 22, Folder 20)
      [Reprint, correspondence, typescript].
    - Exiled Physicians in the United States. (American Scholar), Summer 1943 (Box 22, Folder 21-28)
      [Correspondence, reprints, typescripts, reprints by others, clippings, notes, statistical tables].
    - C. Neumann, W.T. Lhamon, Cohn (C. Galati). A study of factors (emotional) responsible for changes in the pattern of spontaneous rhythmic fluctuations in the volume of the vascular bed of the finger tip. J.C.I. 23, 1-9, 1944; [Galley, typescripts, reprint] (Box 22, Folder 29)
    - On Retirement, continued reprints, clippings, notes, vital statistics of the Justices of the U.S. Supreme Court with Felix Frankfurter/Cohn correspondence, tables, typescripts, C. Lingg correspondence], [[page missing]] (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - [Notes and draft] (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - [Letter to Edward A. Weeks, typescripts] (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - [Vogue clipping, typescripts, correspondence with Yale Review] (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Disease of the Heart. Alpha Omega Alpha, Tulane University Medical School, 1945 March 20 (Box 23)
      - [Programs, clipping, Science reprint] (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - [Clipping from Lancet re Cohn article, galley proof, typescripts], 1945 November 3 (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - First and second copies [of typescript] (Box 23, Folder 11)
      - Summary (sent to Dr. Burch -), 1945 March 9 (Box 23, Folder 12)
        Correspondence [reprint requests and acknowledgements].
    - Remarks - Dinner to Mr. E.C. Lobenstine (5-21-45), 1926-1927 (Box 23, Folder 13)
      [Typescripts, correspondence including copies of exchange with R.K.S. Lim, invitation, holographs].
    - Atom. "Next morning - responsibility", 1945 August 7; [Typescripts, correspondence, clippings, printed material, holographs, Niels Bohr holograph and reprints] (Box 23, Folder 14-15)
    - Research in Cardiovascular Diseases. J. Gerontology 2 11-17, 1947 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Loveman, Miss Amy. Sat. Rev. of Literature (Box 23, Folder 17)
      [re Cohn book reviews of Medicine Today, American Medical Research, and My Life as a Teacher (by John Erskine). Includes correspondence, typescripts, holographs, clippings].
    - Art and Science in One World. Wells College, NY, 1948 December 1 (Box 23, Folder 18-19)
      [Typescripts, holograph notes, letter].
    - The great engine, The Heart. NY Times, Mg. Section, p. 18, 1949 February 13 (Box 23)
      - [Clippings, outline, typescripts, correspondence] (Box 23, Folder 20)
      - [Correspondence and letters of appreciation] (Box 23, Folder 21)
      - [Background material] (Box 23, Folder 22)
      - [C. Lingg letter and tables and graphs], 1948 (Box 23, Folder 23)
      - [Notes, typescripts, holographs] (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - Monument to Medical Historic Scholarship. NY Herald Trib, 1951 August 12 (Box 23, Folder 25)
      [Review of A History of Medicine Vol. 1, by Henry E. Sigerist].
    - University Department Medicine. Memo, on a new journal. COLE (Box 23, Folder 26)
      - Articles by Rufus Cole, M.D., 1920 April; Typescripts, reprints, and stencils
        Includes "The University Department of Medicine," Science 2.
      - "Memorandum concerning the Publication of a New Journal, ", 1921 April 1
      - "Perfectionism in Medicine", Bull. Johns Hopkins Hospital, 1946 August
    - A Mind Lively and Unafraid. NY Herald Trib. Book Rev., 1950 December 3 (Box 24, Folder 1)
      [Review of Speaking of Man by Abraham Myerson. Clippings, correspondence, typescripts, notes, holographs].
    - The Blood in Adult Life, 1953 (Box 24, Folder 2-4)
      [re Cohn article for New York Times Magazine on blood, 1953. Not published. Includes correspondence, typescripts, figures, notes].
    - 4 Chapters from Medicine, Science and Art re-written but omitted from No Retreat from Reason (Box 24)
      - Physiology and Medicine (Box 24, Folder 5)
      - Medicine and Science (Box 24, Folder 6)
      - Purposes in Medical Research (Box 24, Folder 7)
      - Careers in Medicine (formerly The Hierarchy of Medicine) (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - [2 reprints: "Recollections concerning early electrocardiography in the United States, " Bull. Hist. Med. 29: 469-74 ], 1955 September-October (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - SUBJECT FILES (Box 24)